

<u>CONTACT</u>

ymanisha55@gmail.com

+91 9073907391

Ahmedabad, Gujarat

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/manisha-yadav-0747bb110/

SKILLS

- Work Measurement using MODAPTS & Stopwatch Time Study
- Productivity Improvement
 Manpower Planning & Budgeting
- Project Management
- Six Sigma Green Belt
- Kaizen
- Process Excellence
- Supply Chain Optimization
- New Program Launch
- Value Analysis & Value Engineering Ergonomics
- Skill & Capability building
- Training & Development

TRAININGS

- Line balancing, 5S & Kaizen
- Internal trainers at Schneider Electric
- Front-Line Managers Schneider Electric
 India Pvt. Ltd.
- Front Line Leadership Development for Process Coach, Ford Motor Company
- Ergonomics tools, Ergo Web
- Safety, TML& Ford Motor Company
- Management Tools, Harvard Management Mentor

MANISHA YADAV

SENIOR INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Professional with more than 5+ years of experience in Industrial Engineering, Operation Excellence, Lean Manufacturing & HR. A motivator with great interpersonal skills who can keep calm and achieve best results in under pressure situation with teamwork, dedication and confidence.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Industrial Engineer Ford India Pvt. Ltd. (Ford Motor Company)

Feb 2019 to Present

- Work measurement using MODAPTS and stopwatch time study to establish and validate data time study data for various manufacturing functions, Quality & Supply Chain.
- Manpower planning & budgeting based on business requirementdue to work pattern changes, New Program Launch, Capacity Planning etc.
- Identify and Lead manpower efficiency improvement projects to achieve CPU target using Kaizen, Six Sigma GB, Layout Improvement, methodization, line balancing, NVA reduction etc.
- Process allocation and improvement for various areas such as Engine Assembly, Engine Machining and Support functions.
- Ergonomics Analysis & improvement using different tools such as Ergo RX and EST
- New program manpower and process planning and support team to implement changes.

Industrial Engineering Specialist Schneider Electric India Pvt. Ltd.

Jul 2016 to Jan 2019

- Work measurement using MTM, implemented M & MOP in Foundry, Engine & vehicle Assembly.
- Productivity monitoring and improvement using Line Balancing, NVA reduction, Layout Improvement, Capacity enhancement.
- Calculating and increasing productivity through combined work steps, eliminating non- value-added activities and the development of effective work practices.
- Identify opportunity and work out VAVE ideas and implement the same with the help of CFT.
- Digitization of work content data.
- Evaluate work zone for safety, ergonomic concerns and performance criteria Implemented Skill Gap analysis tool and used the same for capability building.
- Support plant to achieved world class quality by standardization & continuous improvement.

EDUCATION

B.E.- MECHANICAL ENGINEERING
Madhav Institute of Technology & Science (MITS)
Gold Medalist with 8.23 CGPA

Aug 2012-May 2016

AWARDS

- Best Continuous Improvement Idea- India –
 2017, Schneider Electric India Pvt. Ltd
- Schneider Electric Learning Champion, 2017
 & 2018, Schneider Electric India Pvt. Ltd.
- Internal Trainer of the year -2019, Schneider
 Electric India Pvt. Ltd.
- Asia Pacific Recognition Award 2019 2
 Awards, Ford India Pvt. Ltd.
- Asia Pacific Recognition Award -2020 2
 Awards, Ford India Pvt. Ltd.
- President Health & Safety Award 2019,
 2020, Ford India Pvt. Ltd
- Asia Pacific Recognition Award 2021, Ford
 India Pvt. Ltd
- Go Further Award -2021, Ford India Pvt. Ltd

PROJECTS

Ford India Pvt. Ltd.

Feb 2019 to Present

- Flexi Operating Pattern Improvement in Machine Shop for 2nd Shift
 Operation with a total Cost saving of \$5000/year. Total Reduction of 9
 Headcounts of 2nd Crew. Over Head Cost saving included.
- Estimated work content using MODAPTS for all stations of Engine Assembly (200+ stations completed, 315+ HC)
- Implemented paperless manpower approval system using Docusign.
- Planning YoY Capacity Planning for the optimized Operating Pattern to reduce the hiring cost and other cost for the plant—decide the Shift Pattern- Time Pattern & working days for the plant. Correlate the shift pattern with the RTO (Required to Operate) Headcounts.
- Maintain HPU/CPU database (Creating the 5-year roadmap for HPU Efficiencies and headcount walk.)
- Handling the Headcounts of Assembly, Machine Shop, MP&L, Quality, and other Departments in PTO
- Lead and drive projects to achieve HC efficiency
- 1. 2019- 37 headcounts (15% YoY efficiency wrt to actual target of 7.5%)
- 2. 2020- 10 headcounts (3.5% YoY efficiency wrt to actual target of 3.5%)
- 3. 2021- 5 headcounts (1.5% YoY efficiency wrt to actual target of 1.5%)

Schneider Electric India Pvt. Ltd.

Jul 2016 to Jan 2019

- Increased the capacity utilization of VCB Mechanism by line balancing & Material flow improvements.
- Improved the cycle time of PCOB breaker by eliminating the debottlenecking, line balancing & Material flow improvements.
- Designed 150+ customized trolley for the lines to improve material handling & process flow.
- Designed the Training & Development plan and Trained over 400 people.
- Trained operators in English and presentation skills
- Won 10+ recognition awards
- criteria Implemented Skill Gap analysis tool and used the same for capability building.
- Support plant to achieved world class quality by standardization & continuous improvement.